<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Phillip J. Wolfram</title>
 <link href="http://pwolfram.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://pwolfram.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2020-02-05T09:02:27-07:00</updated>
 <id>http://pwolfram.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Phillip J. Wolfram</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>E3SM Simulation of Coastal Processes</title>
   <link href="http://pwolfram.github.io/2019/11/01/2019-waves/"/>
   <updated>2019-11-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://pwolfram.github.io/2019/11/01/2019-waves</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;WAVEWATCH III® is being introduced into the Energy Exascale Earth System Model (E3SM) to advance the simulation of coastal processes within the model. &lt;a href=&quot;https://e3sm.org/e3sm-next-generation-development-for-coastal-waves/&quot;&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;video-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ic8ayrMUQlM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>IMUM 2019 Conference</title>
   <link href="http://pwolfram.github.io/2019/10/01/2019-imum/"/>
   <updated>2019-10-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://pwolfram.github.io/2019/10/01/2019-imum</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Thank you to everyone who participated in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cnls.lanl.gov/IMUM/&quot;&gt;The 18th International workshop on Multi-scale (Un)-structured mesh numerical Modeling for coastal, shelf, and global ocean dynamics (IMUM 2019) conference&lt;/a&gt; I co-organized with &lt;a href=&quot;https://mark-petersen.github.io/&quot;&gt;Mark Petersen&lt;/a&gt; this year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://pwolfram.github.io/public/IMUMconf.png&quot; class=&quot;IMUMparticipants&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>LIGHT Great Pacific Garbage Patch</title>
   <link href="http://pwolfram.github.io/2019/08/23/light-garbage-patch/"/>
   <updated>2019-08-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://pwolfram.github.io/2019/08/23/light-garbage-patch</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Video by summer student &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rileyxbrady.com/&quot;&gt;Riley Brady&lt;/a&gt; highlights use of &lt;a href=&quot;http://pwolfram.github.io/light&quot;&gt;LIGHT&lt;/a&gt; in a global domain and demonstrates surface-convergent fluid mechanics behind formation of the Great Pacific Garbage Patch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;video-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/357112846&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/357112846&quot;&gt;The Great Pacific Garbage Patch&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/user96067365&quot;&gt;Riley Brady&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Distinguished Performance Award for E3SM Team</title>
   <link href="http://pwolfram.github.io/2019/07/19/dist-perf-award/"/>
   <updated>2019-07-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://pwolfram.github.io/2019/07/19/dist-perf-award</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://e3sm.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/e3sm-logo.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Los Alamos team was awarded a 2018 Large Team Distinguished Performance Award in ALDSC &amp;amp; ALDGS for the Energy Exascale Earth System Model (E3SM) model, which was released in early 2018. I lead &lt;a href=&quot;https://e3sm.org/about/organization/ngd-sub-projects/ngd-coastal-waves/&quot;&gt;next generation development for coastal waves&lt;/a&gt; in this project.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>LIGHT Southern Ocean Biogeochemistry</title>
   <link href="http://pwolfram.github.io/2019/05/20/surface-bgc-floats/"/>
   <updated>2019-05-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://pwolfram.github.io/2019/05/20/surface-bgc-floats</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Video by summer student &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rileyxbrady.com/&quot;&gt;Riley Brady&lt;/a&gt; highlights use of newly developed and tested biogeochemical and surface float &lt;a href=&quot;http://pwolfram.github.io/light&quot;&gt;LIGHT&lt;/a&gt; capabilities for the Southern Ocean, which will be used to identify hotspots of atmosphere-ocean fluxes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;video-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/337393622&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;512&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/337393622&quot;&gt;Surface BGC Floats in MPAS Ocean&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/user96067365&quot;&gt;Riley Brady&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;video-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/365579177&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay; fullscreen&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/365579177&quot;&gt;The Flow of Dissolved Carbon in the Southern Ocean&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/user96067365&quot;&gt;Riley Brady&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>SciVis 2018 video</title>
   <link href="http://pwolfram.github.io/2019/04/02/scivis-video/"/>
   <updated>2019-04-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://pwolfram.github.io/2019/04/02/scivis-video</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;video-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/315403589&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/315403589&quot;&gt;SciVis 2018: Ocean Current Segmentation at Different Depths and Correlation with Temperature in a MPAS-Ocean Simulation&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/vgtcommunity&quot;&gt;VGTCommunity&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Dean Price wins NEUS award</title>
   <link href="http://pwolfram.github.io/2019/03/12/price-scholarship/"/>
   <updated>2019-03-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://pwolfram.github.io/2019/03/12/price-scholarship</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Highest congratulations to Dean Price, who won a Nuclear Energy Undergraduate Scholarship awarded by the Integrated University Program under the US Department of Energy.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Oliver Fringer Promotion to Full Professor</title>
   <link href="http://pwolfram.github.io/2018/12/07/fringer-promotion/"/>
   <updated>2018-12-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://pwolfram.github.io/2018/12/07/fringer-promotion</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Highest congratulations to my Ph.D. advisor &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.stanford.edu/~fringer/&quot;&gt;Oliver Fringer&lt;/a&gt;, who was just promoted to Stanford Full Professor! I am deeply grateful for your mentorship and the coastal modeling and analysis research community you have built.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Welcome new group members</title>
   <link href="http://pwolfram.github.io/2018/11/15/new-members/"/>
   <updated>2018-11-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://pwolfram.github.io/2018/11/15/new-members</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I warmly welcome Steven Brus and Zhendong Cao who have started working with me as postdocs to develop coastal modeling capabilities in &lt;a href=&quot;http://mpas-dev.github.io/ocean/ocean.html&quot;&gt;MPAS-O&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://e3sm.org/&quot;&gt;E3SM&lt;/a&gt;! Please read more about their interests on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://pwolfram.github.io/people&quot;&gt;People page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>CG&A Cover</title>
   <link href="http://pwolfram.github.io/2018/04/15/cga-cover/"/>
   <updated>2018-04-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://pwolfram.github.io/2018/04/15/cga-cover</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some of our simulation results&lt;span class=&quot;citation&quot; data-cites=&quot;wolfram2017computing wolfram2017eddymeanflow ringler2016thickness&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ref-wolfram2017computing&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;–&lt;a href=&quot;#ref-ringler2016thickness&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/span&gt; were featured as the cover of the journal of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.computer.org/csdl/mags/cg/2018/01/mcg20180100c1.pdf&quot;&gt;Computer Graphics and Applications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; (Fig &lt;a href=&quot;#fig:CGAcover&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;fig:CGAcover&quot; class=&quot;fignos&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://pwolfram.github.io/public/CGAcover.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Figure 1: Computer Graphics and Applications January/February 2018 Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;span&gt;Figure 1:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;Computer Graphics and Applications&lt;/em&gt; January/February 2018 Cover&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;refs&quot; class=&quot;references&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;ref-wolfram2017computing&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Wolfram, P. J.&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; Ringler, T. D. Computing eddy-driven effective diffusivity using Lagrangian particles. &lt;em&gt;Ocean Modell.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;118,&lt;/strong&gt; 94–106 (2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;ref-wolfram2017eddymeanflow&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;Wolfram, P. J.&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; Ringler, T. D. Quantifying residual, eddy, and mean flow effects on mixing in an idealized circumpolar current. &lt;em&gt;J. Phys. Oceanogr.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;47,&lt;/strong&gt; 1897–1920 (2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;ref-ringler2016thickness&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Ringler, T., Saenz, J., &lt;strong&gt;Wolfram, P.J.&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; Van Roekel, L. A thickness-weighted average perspective of force balance in an idealized circumpolar current. &lt;em&gt;J. Phys. Oceanogr.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;47,&lt;/strong&gt; 285–302 (2017).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Postdoc Research Associate Opportunity for Coastal Ocean Modeling in Los Alamos, New Mexico</title>
   <link href="http://pwolfram.github.io/2018/04/12/postdoc/"/>
   <updated>2018-04-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://pwolfram.github.io/2018/04/12/postdoc</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;applications-will-be-reviewed-as-received-apply-now&quot;&gt;Applications will be reviewed as received– &lt;a href=&quot;https://lanl.jobs/los-alamos-nm/postdoc-research-associate-for-coastal-ocean-modeling/203EDC6DF9C548EB93ABC1B4474929A1/job/&quot;&gt;Apply now!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!--
## What You Will Do

The COSIM team seeks applications from diverse candidates with expertise in
coastal, ocean and/or land modeling to work on coastal ocean modeling
development, which may include processes such as inundation, sediment transport
and vegetation, tides, and mixing. We particularly welcome research proposals
for development of novel coastal ocean physics, broadly defined but potentially
including but not limited to sub-grid bathymetry approaches, innovative scalar
transport schemes, mixed-dimensional and multiscale modeling, reduced-order
modeling, coupled land-ocean approaches, etc. The successful candidate will be
part of a multidisciplinary team developing an innovative decadal-scale coastal
model for real-world application. Results from this work will be presented in
conferences and published in peer-reviewed journals. The initial appointment is
for two years, with a possible third year extension depending on performance
and funding availability.

## What You Need

*Desired Skills:* We seek candidates with diverse research experience with a
preference for individuals with one or more of the following:experience and
knowledge of computational physics, coastal modeling, and/or climate modeling;
experience in construction and application of physical models; programing
expertise; and the analysis and incorporation of data and observations for
model development and testing. The candidate will have also demonstrated
scientific excellence as evidenced by submission and publication of authored
publications in refereed journals, and/or the experience and ability to create
or improve computational software.The ability to work in a highly collaborative
team setting is also a requirement.

*Education:* A Ph.D. in earth sciences, civil engineering, geophysics, fluid
dynamics, climate modeling, computational science, physics, applied
mathematics, or a closely related field. Exceptional candidates with a M.S. and
relevant experience will also be considered.

*Notes to Applicants:* In addition to applying on-line, send a curriculum
vitae, digitized copies of transcripts, names of three references, and a
one-page cover letter detailing qualifications, research interests, and a
proposed research topic (1-3 paragraphs) to Phillip Wolfram
(pwolfram@lanl.gov). Please include “Coastal Ocean Modeling 2018 Postdoc
Search” in the email subject line. Applications will be reviewed as received.
We expect to fill up to 2 postdoc positions by August 2018.

*Additional Details:* Position does not require a security clearance. Selected
candidates will be subject to drug testing and other pre-employment background
checks.

*New-Employment Drug Test:* The Laboratory requires successful applicants to
complete a new-employment drug test and maintains a substance abuse policy that
includes random drug testing.

Candidates may be considered for a Director's Fellowship and outstanding
candidates may be considered for the prestigious Darleane Christian Hoffman,
Richard P. Feynman, J. Robert Oppenheimer, or Frederick Reines Fellowships. For
the named fellowship, the research scope can be broadened to include any topic
of mutual interest in the broad coastal and ocean modeling arena, e.g., global
climate modeling, computational physics and algorithms, high performance
computing in heterogeneous architectures, remote sensing, data analysis, data
assimilation, and machine learning. For general, salary, and benefits
information go to Postdoc Program.

## Equal Opportunity

Los Alamos National Laboratory is an equal opportunity employer and supports a
diverse and inclusive workforce. All employment practices are based on
qualification and merit, without regards to race, color, national origin,
ancestry, religion, age, sex, gender identity, sexual orientation or
preference, marital status or spousal affiliation, physical or mental
disability, medical conditions, pregnancy, status as a protected veteran,
genetic information, or citizenship within the limits imposed by federal laws
and regulations. The Laboratory is also committed to making our workplace
accessible to individuals with disabilities and will provide reasonable
accommodations, upon request, for individuals to participate in the application
and hiring process. To request such an accommodation, please send an email to
applyhelp@lanl.gov or call 1-505-665-4444 option 1.

## Where You Will Work

Los Alamos National Laboratory is a multidisciplinary research institution
engaged in science and engineering on behalf of national security. This postdoc
position is within the Climate, Ocean and Sea-Ice Modeling (COSIM) Team that
develops advanced ocean and ice models for the study of climate and climate
change, e.g., the Model for Prediction Across Scales Ocean (MPAS-O) within the
Department of Energy’s Energy Exascale Earth System Model (E3SM). Within this
broad activity, a focus is on the role of coastal zone infrastructure
adaptation, ecogeomorphology for regional climate adaptation, the role of ocean
mesoscale eddies in the climate system, and the role of the ocean and ice
systems in the carbon cycle and sea-level rise.

*Location:* Los Alamos, NM, US

*Organization Name:* T-3/Fluid Dynamics And Solid Mechanics

*Job Title:* Postdoc Research Associate for Coastal Ocean Modeling

*Appointment Type:* Postdoc

*Req ID:* IRC61729
--&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>New site construction</title>
   <link href="http://pwolfram.github.io/2018/01/03/new-site/"/>
   <updated>2018-01-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>http://pwolfram.github.io/2018/01/03/new-site</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This new site is a compilation of several technologies, starting with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://hyde.getpoole.com/&quot;&gt;Hyde&lt;/a&gt; template. &lt;a href=&quot;https://pandoc.org&quot;&gt;Pandoc&lt;/a&gt; support is enabled to provide references and figure captions via &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tomduck/pandoc-fignos&quot;&gt;pandoc-fignos&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;hyde&quot;&gt;Hyde&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://hyde.getpoole.com/&quot;&gt;Hyde&lt;/a&gt; is a brazen two-column &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; theme that pairs a prominent sidebar with uncomplicated content. It’s based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://getpoole.com&quot;&gt;Poole&lt;/a&gt;, the Jekyll butler.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;built-on-poole&quot;&gt;Built on Poole&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poole is the Jekyll Butler, serving as an upstanding and effective foundation for Jekyll themes by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mdo&quot;&gt;@mdo&lt;/a&gt;. Poole, and every theme built on it (like Hyde here) includes the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete Jekyll setup included (layouts, config, &lt;a href=&quot;/404&quot;&gt;404&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/atom.xml&quot;&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt;, posts, and &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;example page&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly design and development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easily scalable text and component sizing with &lt;code&gt;rem&lt;/code&gt; units in the CSS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support for a wide gamut of HTML elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Related posts (time-based, because Jekyll) below each post&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Syntax highlighting, courtesy Pygments (the Python-based code snippet highlighter)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;hyde-features&quot;&gt;Hyde features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the features of Poole, Hyde adds the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sidebar includes support for textual modules and a dynamically generated navigation with active link support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two orientations for content and sidebar, default (left sidebar) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/poole/lanyon#reverse-layout&quot;&gt;reverse&lt;/a&gt; (right sidebar), available via &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; classes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/poole/hyde#themes&quot;&gt;Eight optional color schemes&lt;/a&gt;, available via &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; classes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/poole/hyde#readme&quot;&gt;Head to the readme&lt;/a&gt; to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;browser-support&quot;&gt;Browser support&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyde is by preference a forward-thinking project. In addition to the latest versions of Chrome, Safari (mobile and desktop), and Firefox, it is only compatible with Internet Explorer 9 and above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;download&quot;&gt;Download&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hyde is developed on and hosted with GitHub. Head to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/poole/hyde&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; for downloads, bug reports, and features requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my new site built on &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; a static site generator, an open-source tool for creating simple yet powerful websites of all shapes and sizes. From &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/blob/master/README.markdown&quot;&gt;the project’s readme&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is a simple, blog aware, static site generator. It takes a template directory […] and spits out a complete, static website suitable for serving with Apache or your favorite web server. This is also the engine behind GitHub Pages, which you can use to host your project’s page or blog right here from GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s an immensely useful tool that can be used to produce clean webpages easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find out more by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&quot;&gt;visiting the project on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;publishing&quot;&gt;Publishing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sitepoint.com/jekyll-plugins-github/&quot;&gt;Full instructions&lt;/a&gt;, simplified below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;initial-setup&quot;&gt;Initial setup&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In root directory for site folder, make a copied folder, e.g., &lt;code&gt;cp -r pwolfram.github.io compiled_site&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd compiled_site&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean it up: &lt;code&gt;rm -r *; git rm -r * -f&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;touch .nojekyll&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;git add .nojekyll&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;git add --all :/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;git commit -m &amp;quot;Built site locally&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;git push origin master:master&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note, this doesn’t keep a copy of the source in the repo!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;automating-the-full-process&quot;&gt;Automating the full process&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make a &lt;code&gt;Rakefile&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sourceCode&quot; id=&quot;cb1&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;sourceCode rake&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;sourceCode ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;sourceLine&quot; id=&quot;cb1-1&quot; data-line-number=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dt&quot;&gt;GH_PAGES_DIR&lt;/span&gt; = &lt;span class=&quot;st&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;compiled_site&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;sourceLine&quot; id=&quot;cb1-2&quot; data-line-number=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;sourceLine&quot; id=&quot;cb1-3&quot; data-line-number=&quot;3&quot;&gt;desc &lt;span class=&quot;st&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Build Jekyll site and copy files&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;sourceLine&quot; id=&quot;cb1-4&quot; data-line-number=&quot;4&quot;&gt;task &lt;span class=&quot;st&quot;&gt;:build&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kw&quot;&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;sourceLine&quot; id=&quot;cb1-5&quot; data-line-number=&quot;5&quot;&gt;system &lt;span class=&quot;st&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;jekyll build&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;sourceLine&quot; id=&quot;cb1-6&quot; data-line-number=&quot;6&quot;&gt;system &lt;span class=&quot;st&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;rm -r ../&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ot&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dt&quot;&gt;GH_PAGES_DIR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ot&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;st&quot;&gt;/*&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kw&quot;&gt;unless&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;dt&quot;&gt;Dir&lt;/span&gt;[&lt;span class=&quot;st&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;../#{GH_PAGES_DIR}/*&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;].empty?&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;sourceLine&quot; id=&quot;cb1-7&quot; data-line-number=&quot;7&quot;&gt;system &lt;span class=&quot;st&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;cp -r _site/* ../&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ot&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;dt&quot;&gt;GH_PAGES_DIR&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ot&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;st&quot;&gt;/&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;sourceLine&quot; id=&quot;cb1-8&quot; data-line-number=&quot;8&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kw&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ensure that &lt;code&gt;exclude: [Rakefile]&lt;/code&gt; is appended to &lt;code&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can use the following script to automate pushing of the site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;sourceCode&quot; id=&quot;cb2&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;sourceCode bash&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;sourceCode bash&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;sourceLine&quot; id=&quot;cb2-1&quot; data-line-number=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;ex&quot;&gt;rake&lt;/span&gt; build&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;sourceLine&quot; id=&quot;cb2-2&quot; data-line-number=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;sourceLine&quot; id=&quot;cb2-3&quot; data-line-number=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;bu&quot;&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; ../compiled_site&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;sourceLine&quot; id=&quot;cb2-4&quot; data-line-number=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;fu&quot;&gt;git&lt;/span&gt; add --all&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;sourceLine&quot; id=&quot;cb2-5&quot; data-line-number=&quot;5&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;fu&quot;&gt;git&lt;/span&gt; commit -m &lt;span class=&quot;st&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Published &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kw&quot;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;fu&quot;&gt;date&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kw&quot;&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;st&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;sourceLine&quot; id=&quot;cb2-6&quot; data-line-number=&quot;6&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;fu&quot;&gt;git&lt;/span&gt; push origin master:master&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
